Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Alun Jones Papers, 1930-1984 RL.00718
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Alun Jones papers
1930-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00718
3.75 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Alun Jones was a financial executive at JWT's Toronto and New York offices during the 1960s-1970s, holding the positions of Secretary-Treasurer and Executive Vice-President; he was elected to JWT's Board of Directors in 1974. The Alun Jones Papers cover the years 1930-1984, with the bulk of the collection dating from the late 1970s, and contains files primarily relating to Jones's work as a financial executive and administrator at the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT). The collection consists of memoranda, correspondence, and reports covering topics including audits, agency compensation, management incentive plans and other company policies, and files related to financial matters at JWT's offices including Chicago, Detroit, New York and San Francisco, as well as JWT's international offices including Australia, Canada, and South Africa. Clients represented include Burger King, Kodak, Kraft, and Lever Brothers (Unilever). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
5600 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Alun Jones Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Chronology List
Chronology
1956 Relocated to Canada
1960 Account Supervisor, J. Walter Thompson Limited (Canada)
1960 Financial Manager, JWT Toronto
1965 Assistant Secretary-Treasurer, JWT Toronto
1968 Secretary-Treasurer and Director, JWT Canada
1970 Senior Vice President and Director of Finance and Administration, JWT Canada
1972 Senior Vice President, Business Management, JWT New York
1974 Feb. Senior Vice President-Finance, JWT New York
1974 May Executive Vice President-Finance; elected to Board of Directors of JWT
Alun Jones was born in Wales and was educated at Magdalen College School in England. He was an Associate of the Chartered Institute of Secretaries.
Collection Overview
The Alun Jones Papers cover the years 1930-1984, with the bulk of the collection dating from the late 1970s, and contains files primarily relating to Jones's work as a financial executive and administrator at the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT). The collection consists of memoranda, correspondence, and reports covering topics including audits, agency compensation, management incentive plans and other company policies, and files related to financial matters at JWT's offices including Chicago, Detroit, New York and San Francisco, as well as JWT's international offices including Australia, Canada, and South Africa. Clients represented include Burger King, Kodak, Kraft, and Lever Brothers (Unilever).
Related Material
Related material can be found in the following collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives at the Hartman Center:
Account Files
Advertising Vertical Files
Biographical Information
Corporate Documentation
Iconographic Collection
Hugh P. Connell Papers
Herbert Eames Papers
Victor Gutierrez Papers
John R. Maher Papers
Jack Peters Papers
In addition, related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collection:
McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File
Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- South Africa; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Australia; Advertising agencies -- Canada; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company; Jones, Alun; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Unilever (Firm); Kraft Foods Company; J. Walter Thompson Company; Eastman Kodak Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; Burger King Corporation
- Administrative Files, 1974-1980, 5 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains general files of memoranda, correspondence, and reports covering such topics as audits, agency compensation, the management incentive plan, and other company policies.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by topic. Original folder titles were maintained.
  - Account Analysis, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Account Control J. Walter Thompson Company Recommendations to Improve Internal Accounting Control, Administrative Efficiency, and Financial Management, 1978 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
  - Administration, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Agency compensation guidelines, 1976, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Alun Jones files, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Art studio sale, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Audit Committee, 1975-1980, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Axion Market Research Bureau, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting, 1974 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Capital budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Challenges and responses, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Continental Corporation, 1973-1980, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Corporate Communications, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Corporate objectives: J. Walter Thompson Company 1977 Corporate Objectives and 1977 Priorities, 1976 (Box 1)
  - David Soskin/Thompson, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - Deltakos, 1977-1978, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Diners/Fugazy Travel and Incentive Company, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Directors and officers, 1984 Mar. 1 (Box 2)
  - Dividend policy, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Dividends, 1975, 1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Eastern Region review, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Employment benefits, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Executive compensation, 1974-1980 (Box 2)
  - Finance managers' meeting, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Going private, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Gordon Hill Advertising Limited, 1979 Sept. 7 (Box 2)
  - Hill and Knowlton, Inc., 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Insurance summaries, 1977-1979 June 1, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Internal Accounting Control Recommendations, Dec. 31, 1977 Examinations, 1977 Dec. 31 (Box 2)
  - Internal Control Standards Manual, 1979 Jan. 1 (Box 2)
  - Lansdowne Advertising, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Management benefits, 1978 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Management Incentive Plan, 1977-1980, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Monitoring results, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - North American Operations Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Chairman, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Personnel policies, 1978-1980, 1 of 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Personnel policies, 1978-1980 (continued), 2 of 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Plans, 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Policies, 1966, 1977-1979 (Box 4)
  - Price Waterhouse, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Procedure on Intercompany Transfers, 1974 June 14 (Box 4)
  - Questions for TV interview, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Research, 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Retirement contracts, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
  - Retirement Trust, 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Simmons Market Research Bureau, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Stock, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - Stock Incentive Plan project, 1975 June (Box 5)
  - Supermarket media, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Survival Anglia, Ltd., 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Three year plan, 1978-1979, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - U.S. company, 1976, 1980 (Box 5)
  - U.S. Eastern Division Update Spring 1978, 1978 June 7 (Box 5)
  - U.S. managers' meeting, 1979 (Box 5)
  - U.S. Western Division, 1978 (Box 5)
  - World Wide Agency, Inc., 1979 Dec. (Box 5)
- Clients, 1975-1980, 1 box
  Contains files of memoranda, correspondence, and reports on several JWT clients.
  Arranged alphabetically, then chronologically
  - Beatrice Foods, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Burger King, 1976-1978, 1 of 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Burger King, 1976-1978 (continued), 2-5 of 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Chevron A Compensation Proposal for a Partnership between Cheven USA and JWT, 1977 Aug. (Box 6)
  - Ford, 1971-1975
    [Oversized proofs for Ford Pinto and Maverick, 1971 removed to JWT Domestic Advertisements Collection.]
    - General, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
    - FDAF (Ford Dealers Advertising Fund) financial review, 1977 (Box 6)
    - FDAF meeting, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
  - Gillette, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Kodak, 1930-1980, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Kraft, 1977-1979, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Lever, 1976-1978, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Oscar Mayer Oscar Mayer and JWT Together, 1977 Sept. 21 (Box 6)
  - Top Worldwide and U.S. Clients, 1975-1979 (Box 6)
- Domestic Offices, 1975-1979, 1 box
  Contains files related to financial matters on JWT's domestic offices in Chicago, Detroit, Los Angeles, Miami, and New York.
  - Chicago
    - General, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - Chicago Plan, 1978, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Detroit
    - General, 1975-1978 (Box 7)
    - 1977 Financial Plan, 1976 Sept. 13 (Box 7)
    - 1977 Preliminary Outlook, 1976 Sept. 13 (Box 7)
    - 1978 Financial Plan, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Office Space Recommendations, 1978 Jan. 1 (Box 7)
    - Sales Promotion Final Review of 1975 Operations, 1975 Nov. 1 (Box 7)
    - Sales Promotion Review of 1976 Operations...Plans for 1977, 1976 Nov. 1 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles
    - 1977 Preliminary Plan, 1976 Oct. 22 (Box 7)
  - Miami
    - Operating Procedure Guide for the Establishment of JWT Miami, 1977 Sept. 30 (Box 7)
  - New York
    - General, 1976-1979, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - JWT New York A Financial Overview, 1979 Sept. 4 (Box 7)
    - New York Advertising Annual Management Assessment/Objectives, 1976 1976 Jan. 15 (Box 7)
    - New York Office Advertising and Public Relations Plan, 1976 May 1 (Box 7)
    - New York Office 1977 Preliminary Profit Plan Advertising and Public Relations, 1976 Oct. 22 (Box 7)
    - Operations Planning Reviews, 1978 Nov. 7 (Box 7)
    - Project 33%, 1978 Aug. 21 (Box 7)
    - Review, 1978 (Box 7)
  - San Francisco
    - General, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
    - 1977 Preliminary Profit Plan San Francisco Office, 1976 Sept. 1 (Box 7)
    - San Francisco Office 1976 Preliminary Profit Plan, 1975 Nov. (Box 7)
  - Washington, D.C.
    - JWT Washington 1977 Preliminary Plans and Objectives, 1976 Nov. 5 (Box 7)
- International Offices, 1971-1980, 1 box
  Contains memoranda, correspondence, and reports related to JWT's international offices in Amsterdam, Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Chile, France, Germany, India, Japan, Puerto Rico, South Africa, and the United Kingdom.
  Arranged alphabetically. Original folder titles were maintained.
  - AMPAC Division, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Amsterdam, 1971, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Argentina, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Australia, 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Australia--Begg, Dow, Priddy, Pty., Ltd., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Brazil, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Canada, 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Chile, 1974-1978 (Box 8)
  - France, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
  - Germany, 1979 (Box 8)
  - India, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Japan, 1975, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Puerto Rico, 1974-1975, 1978 (Box 8)
  - South Africa, 1977-1979, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - United Kingdom, 1978-1979 (Box 8)